Guide to the Frank H. T. Rhodes papers,1977-1996.
Rhodes, Frank H. T. papers, 1977-1996.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Frank H. T. Rhodes papers, 1977-1996.
3-12-1795
Frank Harold Trevor Rhodes
360 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, subject files, background material, photographs, transcripts and drafts of speeches, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records relating to Rhodes' Presidency of Cornell University; papers consist of the routine administrative operation of the University; chief concerns include the University's financial development and alumni relations; relations between the University and research corporations and science foundations; the administration of colleges and units relating principally to programs, personnel, and academic matters; and the social role of the President.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
President of Cornell University from 1977-1995.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, reports, subject files, background material, photographs, transcripts and drafts of speeches, and other records relating to Rhodes' Presidency of Cornell University; papers consist of the routine administrative operation of the University; chief concerns include the University's financial development and alumni relations; relations between the University and research corporations and science foundations; the administration of colleges and units relating principally to programs, personnel, and academic matters; and the social role of the President. The papers include the records of the Office of the Provost.
Topics of concern include the restructuring of the University's administrative and academic units; relations with the Board of Trustees; construction and development of facilities and buildings; student deportment and political activism, chiefly concerning South African divestment and Latino issues; affirmative action and minority affairs; academic freedom; employee benefits; the visit to the campus of the Dalai Lama and Chinese President Lee Teng-Hui; community relations; the Cornell University Medical College; and athletics, Title IX, and gender equity.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rhodes, Frank Harold Trevor.; Bstan-'dzin-rgya-mtsho, 1935-; United States. Education Amendments of 1972. Title IX.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University--Buildings.; Cornell University--Endowments.; Cornell University--Finance.; Cornell University--Planning.; Cornell University--Presidents.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University. President.; Cornell University. Provost.; Cornell University. Campus Council.; Cornell University. Committee on Special Education Projects.; Cornell University. Board of Trustees.; Johnson Graduate School of Management (Cornell University)
Subjects:
Universities and colleges--Accreditation.; Universities and colleges--Evaluation.; Academic freedom.; Affirmative action programs.
Places:
China.; Hong Kong.; Japan.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of office of origin. Consult the University Archivist. Restriction reviews may take up to a month for completion.
SERIES LIST
Series I. 1977-1978
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series II. 1978-1979
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series III. 1979-1980
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series IV. 1980-1981
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series V. 1981-1982
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series VI. 1982-1983
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series VII. 1983-1984
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series VIII. 1984-1985
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series IX. 1985-1986
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series X. 1986-1987
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series XI. 1987-1988
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series XII. 1988-1989
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series XIII. 1989-1990
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series XIV. 1990-1991
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series XV. 1991-1992
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series XVI. 1992-1993
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series XVII. 1993-1994
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series XVIII. 1994-1995
Presidential/Administrative
Provost's Files
Subject Files
Series XIX. Speeches
Series XX. Dalai Lama Records
Series XXI. Miscellaneous Reports
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. 1977-1978
  - Presidential/Administrative
    - Office of the President
      - General Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Malott, Deane W.; Kiplinger, Austin H.
      - General Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Rhodes' Christmas letter, December 1977.
      - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Science Symposium, West Germany.
      - General Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        National politics.
      - General Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Whitlock, John H.
      - Condolences, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Condolences, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Cornell, Hollis E.
      - Congratulations, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Holland, Jerome H.
      - Congratulations, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Ammons, A. R.
      - Congratulations, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Sagan, Carl; White, E. B.; Lurie, Alison; King, Joseph P.; Lowi, Theodore J.
      - Congratulations, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Bronfenbrenner, Urie; McHugh, Matthew F. Kellogg Foundation; Lilly Endowment; Community relations; Cornell Medal.
      - Congratulations, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Congratulations, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Sagan, Carl.
      - Congratulations, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Invitations, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
      - Sage Chapel Programs, 1966-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Presidential Councillors Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Newbury, George A.; Olin, John M.; Collyer, John L.; Rebmann, G. Ruhland.
      - Presidential Councillors Meeting, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Site Visits: Colleges, Libraries, Physical Education Facilities, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Site Visits: School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Site Visits: College of Engineering, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Site Visits: College of Engineering, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        Synchrotron.
      - Site Visits: College of Engineering, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Site Visits: Graduate School of Business and Public Administration, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
      - Site Visits: Division of Biological Sciences, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Site Visits: School of Veterinary Medicine, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Site Visits: College of Architecture, Art & Planning, School of Hotel Administration, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Site Visits: College of Arts and Sciences, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Site Visits: College of Arts and Sciences, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Site Visits: New York State College of Human Ecology, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Site Visits: New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Cornell Cooperative Extension, Geneva Experimental Station, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Social Events, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
        Purcell, Robert W.
      - Social Events, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
        Telluride Association.
      - Social Events, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
        Brodeur, Arthur W.; Malott, Deane W.; George Junior Republic.
    - Executive Staff
      - Miscellaneous, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 37)
        McKinsey Report on Administrative Effectiveness.
      - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Assistant to the President
      - General, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
        Barlow, Robert; Research issues; Tuition policy; Title IX; federal relations.
      - General, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 40)
        Barlow, Robert; Mail system; Research issues.
    - Judicial Boards
      - General, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Senior Vice President
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
        Herbster, William G.; Title IX.
      - General, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        Herbster, William G.; Performance appraisals.
      - Office of Personnel Services; (OPS) - General, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
        Herbster, William G.; Willers, Diedrich; Employee relations; Performance appraisals.
      - OPS - General, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        Herbster, William G.; Willers, Diedrich; Personnel data system; Employee relations; Affirmative action.
      - OPS - Collective Bargaining, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        Herbster, William G.; Willers, Diedrich.
      - OPS - Fringe Benefits, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        Herbster, William G.; Knapp, David C.; McConnell study; Affirmative action; Cornell Children's Tuition Scholarship Plan;.
      - OPS - Middle Management, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        Knapp, David C.; Thomas, G.S.
      - OPS - Personnel Data, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        Herbster, William G.; Willers, Diedrich; Lawrence, Samuel A.
      - OPS - Personnel Planning and Policy Board, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        Gurowitz, William D.; Herbster, William G.; Affirmative Action Advisory Board;; Affirmative action; Employee relations.
      - OPS - Personnel Planning and Policy Board, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        Herbster, William G.; Willers, Diedrich; Minimum wage; Affirmative action; Holidays.
      - OPS - Personnel Policies and Procedures, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        Herbster, William G.; Willers, Diedrich; Knapp, David C.; Kammen, Michael; Performance appraisals.
      - Physical Education and Athletics, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        Schultz, Richard; Council of Ivy Group Presidents; Athletic recruiting and admission standards; Schoellkopf Hall; Title IX.
      - Physical Education and Athletics, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        Schultz, Richard; Holland, Joseph; Robison, Ellis H.; National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA); House Sub-committee on Oversight and Investigations; Minority students at Cornell; Athletic recruiting and admission standards; Buckley Amendment; Title IX; Schoellkopf Hall; Donor relations.
      - Physical Education and Athletics, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
        Schultz, Richard; Holland, Joseph; Robison, Ellis H.; Minority students at Cornell; Schoellkopf Hall; Donor relations.
      - Physical Education and Athletics - National Collegiate Athletic Association, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
        Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women (AIAW); Council of Ivy Group Presidents; House Sub-committee on Oversight and Investigations; University of Nevada. Antitrust laws.
      - Salaries, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
        Herbster, William G.; Willers, Diedrich; Minimum wage.
    - University Auditor
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
        Herbster, William G.; Knapp, David C.
    - University Counsel
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
        Stamp, Neal R.; Carey, Hugh L.; Cornell Gay Liberation; Not-for-profit corporation law; SUNY; Gay rights; Sexual discrimination; Suicide; Campus bridge safety.
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
        Stamp, Neal R.; Lake, Charles W.; Cooke, Constance E.; Muka, Betty O.; Kram, Daniel; Trustee elections; Chapter 747; University bylaws; Reverse discrimination; Suicide; Campus bridge safety.
    - Vice President for Financial Aid Planning Services
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 21-25)
        Lawrence, Samuel A.; Tuition policy; Quarterly Financial Review; Administrative Council.
      - Budget Discussion Papers, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
        Kiplinger, Austin H.; Noyes, Jansen; Tuition policy.
      - Budget Discussion Papers, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        Lawrence, Samuel A.; Herbster, William G.; Whitlock, John H.
      - Budget Discussion Papers, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        Lawrence, Samuel A.; Knapp, David C.; Cornell University Medical College.
      - Budget Office, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
        Lawrence, Samuel A.; Knapp, David C.
      - Bursar's Office, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Controller, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        Ostrom, John S.; Lawrence, Samuel A.; Herbster, William G.; Knapp, David C.
      - Controller, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 32)
        Ostrom, John S.; Financial legislation.
      - Institutional Information, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        Stewart, Ian R.
      - Institutional Information, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 34)
        Knapp, David C.
      - Institutional Information, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
        Knapp, David C.; Herbster, William G.
      - Institutional Information, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        Knapp, David C.; Statutory Fact Book
      - Institutional Information, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
        Financial Profile: A Statistical Review of Recent Financial Trends at Cornell University.
      - Office of Computer Services, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 38)
        Lawrence, Samuel A.; Herbster, William G.; Knapp, David C.; Synchrotron.
      - Payroll Officer, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        Bucklin, George.
      - Responsibility Centers Analysis, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 40)
        Ostrom, John S.
    - Treasurer and Vice President
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 41)
        Horn, Robert T.; Dormitory Authority of the State of New York.
      - Laboratory of Ornithology, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Vice President for Campus Affairs
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 43-44)
        Gurowitz, William D.; South African investment; Campus governance; Coalition for Humanism; Student mental health; Suicide; Fall Break.
      - Cornell United Religious Work (CURW), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 45)
        Center for Religion, Ethics and Social Policy (CRESP).
      - Campus Store, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Conference Director, 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 47)
        Conference Policy Committee; Debt collection.
      - Dean of Students, 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 48-49)
        Meyer, Elmer.
      - Dining, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        Gurowitz, William D. Risley Residential College.
      - Housing, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
        Gurowitz, William D.; McHugh, Matthew F.; Psi Upsilon fraternity; Housing and Urban Development; Program houses; student housing shortage.
      - Interreligious International Ministry, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - International Students Office, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
        Perkins, James A.
      - Placement - Career Center, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Department of Public Safety, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
        Gurowitz, William D.; Parking.
      - Department of Public Safety (DPS), 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
        Parking.
      - DPS - Contingency Planning, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
        Jones, W. D.; Campus disruptions; inclement weather.
      - DPS - Policies, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
        Gurowitz, William D.; Knapp, David C.; Hoffman, Roald; Inclement weather.
      - Transportation, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - University Health Services, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
        Ley, Allyn B.; Gurowitz, William D.; Racker, Efraim; Suicide; Gannett Health Center.
      - University Health Services, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        Gurowitz, William D.; Student mental health; Suicide.
      - University Health Services, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        Ley, Allyn B.; Nissenson, Leonard. Suicide; Gannett Health Center.
      - University Unions, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Vice President for Facilities and Business Operations
      - General, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        Desch, Noel; Matyas, Robert M.; Farrell, Robert T.; Fall Creek Hydrogenerating facility.
      - Planning and Facilities, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        Herbster, William G.; Knapp, David C.; Kammen, Michael; Fall Creek Hydrogenerating facility.
      - Energy Conservation, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
        McHugh, Matthew F.
      - General Services, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
        Cornell Club of New York; Tompkins County Airport; Sutton Terrace Apartments.
      - Travel Office, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
        McHugh, Matthew F.; Kahn, Alfred E.
      - Insurance, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Real Estate, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
        Llenroc.
    - Vice President for Public Affairs
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
        Ramin, Richard M.; Snee, Katherine Reinhardt; Affirmative action; Staff directory.
      - Alumni - General, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 23)
        Sherman, Marie Antoinette Brown; University of Liberia; Willard Straight Hall takeover.
      - Alumni - General, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 24)
        Sagan, Carl; White, E. B.; Snee, Katherine Reinhardt; Saperston, Alfred M.; Affirmative action; Pulitzer Prize.
      - Alumni - General, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
        Saperston, Alfred M.
      - Alumni - General, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
        Corson, Dale R.; Cornell medal.
      - Alumni - General, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
        Elm tree crisis.
      - Alumni - General, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 28)
        Reunion.
      - Alumni News, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Alumni Trips, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
        Saperston, Alfred M.; Sauer, William K.; Eddy, Donald; Calspan (Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory); Department of Rare Books; Divestment; Student protests.
      - Alumni Trips, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Alumni Trips, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 32)
        Uris, Harold D.; Johnson, Herbert F.; Olin, Spencer T.; Clark, Hays; Schoales, Dudley N.
      - Alumni Trips, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 33)
        Knight, John S.
      - Alumni Trips, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 34)
        Seeley G. Mudd Fund.
      - Alumni Trips, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 35)
        Atlantic Richfield Company (ARCO).
      - Cornell Adult University, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Campus Club of Cornell, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Chamber of Commerce, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Committee on Corporate Support of Higher Education, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Cornell Chronicle, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Community Relations, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 41)
        Tompkins County Area Development Company.
      - Cornell Fund, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Cornell Daily Sun, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 43)
        Student protests.
      - Cornell University Council, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 44)
        Corson, Dale R. Taiwanese relations.
      - Cornell University Council, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 45)
        Ramin, Richard M.
      - Development - Biographies, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 46)
        Hardin, George D.; Noll, Marie Underhill; Johnson, Belton Kleberg; Silbert, Joseph.
      - Development - Gifts, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 47)
        Li, Shu-Tien; Hales, Battle; World Open University Graduate School; Snee endowment.
      - Development - Gifts, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 48)
        Hertzberg, Benjamin; Hertzberg, Lillian; Neurobiology and Behavior building; Uihlein Meristem facility.
      - Development - Gifts, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Development Office, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - Development Office, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 51)
        Hertzberg, Benjamin; Hertzberg, Lillian; Robison, Ellis H.; J. M. Kaplan Fund.
      - Development Office, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 52)
        Law School gifts.
      - Development Office, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 53)
        Snee, Katherine Reinhardt; Ripley, Joseph P.; Freudenthal, David; Freudenthal, Harriet; Cornell, Hollis E.; Cornell, Marjorie.
      - Development Office, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 54)
        Thomas, Leonard; Preston Thomas Lecture Fund; Campus Club of Cornell; Not-for-profit corporation law; Women at Cornell.
      - Development Office - Major Gifts Campaign, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 55-58)
        Lawrence, Samuel A.; Ramin, Richard M.; Handlan, Raymond L.; Knight, Lester B.
      - Development Office - Major Gifts Campaign, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
        Ramin, Richard M.; Handlan, Raymond L.; Knapp, David C.
      - Endowment Fund, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Corporate Relations, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        Hewlett Packard; Intel; National Semiconductor; Watkins Johnson Company; Standard Oil of California.
      - Corporate Relations, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        General Motors Corporation; Goulds Pumps; New York State Electric and Gas (NYSEG).
      - Corporate Relations, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        Eastman Kodak Company.
      - Corporate Relations, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        Xerox Corporation; Frank E. Gannett Newspaper Foundation.
      - Corporate Relations - Miscellaneous Meetings, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        IBM.
      - Corporate Relations - Miscellaneous Meetings, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Corporate Relations - Miscellaneous Meetings, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        Eastman Kodak Company; United States Steel Foundation; Carrier Corporation; Proctor & Gamble Company.
      - Corporate Relations - Miscellaneous Meetings, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
        New York State Electric and Gas (NYSEG); Sears, Roebuck and Company; DuPont.
      - Corporate Relations - Miscellaneous Meetings, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Corporate Relations - Miscellaneous Meetings, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        IBM; General Motors Corporation.
      - Development, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
        Alger, Mary Donlon; Noyes, Nicholas H.; Dale R. Corson's retirement.
      - Development, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 15-17)
        Noyes, Nicholas H.; Black, Max; Eli Lilly and Company.
      - Public Information, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
        Robey, Bryant; Kiplinger, Austin H.; Tuition policy; Kiplinger dialogue.
      - Public Information, 1977-78 (Box 4, Folder 19)
        Robey, Bryant; Brodeur, Arthur W.; Suicide.
      - Regional Offices, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - University Publications, 1977-78 (Box 4, Folder 21)
        Title IX; Gender-free language; Gay rights; Student rights.
      - Press Conferences, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
        Olin Corporation; Cornell Daily Sun; South Africa; SUNY; Tenure; Financial aid.
      - Press Conferences, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
        Pew Charitable Trust; Cornell University Medical College; Coalition for Humanism; Inauguration; Student mental health; Medical College finances.
      - Press Conferences, 1972-1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
        Calspan; Arvin Industries; Freedom of expression; Chapter 747 (forty-percent rule).
      - University Relations Director, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 25)
        Brodeur, Arthur W.; South African investment.
      - University Relations Director, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 26)
        Brodeur, Arthur W.; Robey, Bryant; Farrell, Robert T.; Investment Advisory Committee; Center for the Study of the American Political Economy (CAPE); Central Intelligence Agency; Reverse discrimination; South African investment; Classified research; MK-ULTRA behavior control program; "War on Illiteracy," writing program; Student housing shortage; Mandatory retirement.
      - University Relations Director, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 27)
        Brodeur, Arthur W.; Ujamaa; Cornell trees.
    - Cornell University Medical College
      - Executive Faculty Council - Agendas and Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 28)
        Genetic research.
      - EFC - Agendas and Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 29-30)
      - EFC - Agendas and Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 31)
        Academic Staff List
      - General Faculty Council - Agendas and Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 32)
        Geriatrics.